# Marianne Costa Avalone

Cachoeira do Sul, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

marianne.avalone@gmail.com

51994572427

linkedin.com/in/mariannecosta

# Summary

For over 17 years I have been dedicated to the research and development of optimization, customization, and building flexibility strategies for the offer of residential units that can be more suitable and last longer. My journey has been motivated by thoughts, plans, and actions guided by information. Therefore, I look for professional challenges where I can use my research and data analytic skills to contribute to decision-making regarding the built environment to better suiting people's demands and diverse lifestyles.

## **Experience**



# 🌟 Junior Programmer

SaibroTech

Jul 2022 - Present (3 months +)

Back-End Development (Python)

- Database Concept (MySQL)
- Database Modeling (Django)
- Deployment (Docker)



#### **Lecturer**

Universidade Federal de Santa Maria

Oct 2020 - Present (2 years +)

Teaching drawing, building construction and career planning in architecture

#### Postdoctoral Researcher

PPGEP/UFSC - Programa de Pós-Graduação em Engenharia de Produção

Jan 2019 - Feb 2021 (2 years 2 months)

Planning and development of research, data analysis using bibliometrics and clustering, report and article writing, editing, and reviewing in collaboration with other researchers.



#### Information Analyst

Sebrae Santa Catarina

Jun 2017 - Jul 2017 (2 months)

Research, content development, and writing of business intelligence reports and trend bulletins for different industry sectors to offer an informational foundation for decision-making to help small and startup businesses prosper in a competitive environment.

## **Assistant Planning Consultant**

PD System Corporation / Subsidiary of the Shimizu Group Apr 2016 - Feb 2017 (11 months)

#### **Junior Architect**

#### Bragaglia Arquitetura

May 2009 - Mar 2010 (11 months)

Worked closely with one of the partners and his associate, at the first year of implementation of the company's second office, in Florianopolis.

Responsible by streamlining the schematic, design development and construction document phases. Was deeply involved with the design of about 12,000 m2 of residential, commercial and institutional buildings in eleven months.

Projects included single detached houses, renovation of apartment units, clothing retail, food retail, supermarkets, and institutions in the south of Brazil.

Clients included: Hippo, Koch, Muffato and Zoni (supermarket chains), and OCESC (Organization of Cooperatives of the state of Santa Catarina).

#### **Junior Architect**

#### Cymaco Empreiteira

Feb 2009 - May 2009 (4 months)

Worked with design proposals for retrofitting of multistory buildings.

Responsible for preparing presentation drawings using computer graphic software such as: AutoCAD, Sketch UP, 3ds Max and Corel Draw.

Projects included façade renovation of 20-30 year old apartment and office buildings in the city of Florianopolis.

#### **Education**

Bachelor, Architecture and Urbanism 2003 - 2008

# **Chiba University**

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Urban Environment Systems 2013 - 2016

# Chiba University

Master's Degree, Urban Environment Systems 2011 - 2013

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- in Grant Writing for Education LinkedIn
- Project Management Foundations LinkedIn
- in Microsoft Project 2016 Essential Training LinkedIn

- in BIM Foundations LinkedIn
- in BIM Management: Careers LinkedIn
- in Creating a BIM Execution Plan LinkedIn
- BIM Manager: Managing CAD Standards LinkedIn
- in BIM Manager: Managing BIM 360 LinkedIn
- in Become a BIM Coordinator LinkedIn
- Revit to Unreal for Architecture, Visualization, and VR LinkedIn
- Stay Ahead in Architecture with Algorithmic Design LinkedIn
- Python for Non-Programmers LinkedIn
- in Python Essential Training LinkedIn
- Python Fundamentals Track DataCamp #291,150
- Python Programming Track DataCamp #294,197
- (A) Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- Intermediate SQL DataCamp #25,512,036
- **Database Experience** Digital Innovation One Inc. 80F9EE45

## **Skills**

Python (Programming Language) • Django • SQL • Git • Microsoft Visual Studio Code • Microsoft Excel • IBM SPSS • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Mendeley

### **Honors & Awards**

# **Award of Excellence** - Japanese Technical Organization for Commercial Spaces - J-TOCS

Jan 2012

9th "Shop" Student Design Competition

The society after Tohoku earthquake: possibilities over commerce and urban development

**MEXT Scholarship for Research Students** - Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, Japan Mar 2013

**MEXT Scholarship for Research Students** - Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, Japan Mar 2010

Institutional Scientific Initiation Scholarship - National Council for Scientific and Technological Development, Brazil

Aug 2005